Spock War Posters Collection
Spock War Posters Collection
1909-1975
Spock, Benjamin, 1903-1998.
229 items
Posters from World War I, World War II and the Vietnam War. Majority are American but there are a few from France, Canada, Italy and England as well. Subjects include recruitment, fund-raising, civil defense, morale-building and more. Organizations represented include the Red Cross; U.S. Army, Navy, Air Force and Marine Corps; various relief committees; more.
2828848
Biographical History
Before the widespread presence of television and radio, and to a lesser extent even after, wartime governments often used posters to broadcast to the civilian population important themes such as civil defense, recruitment, morale-boosting and fund-raising. In many cases notable artists would be engaged to create the illustrations.
World War I and World War II were particularly rich in these cheap and omnipresent pieces of propaganda. According to the Smithsonian Institution's "Produce for Victory: Posters on the American Home Front":
Addressing every citizen as a combatant in the war of production, wartime posters united the power of art with the power of advertising to sell the idea that the factory and the home were also arenas of war. Poster campaigns aimed not only to increase productivity in factories, but also to enlarge people's views of their responsibilities in a time of total war...
[P]eople would encounter posters in places that other media couldn't reach—schools, factories, offices, store windows, and other places outside the scope of paid advertising. Second, posters had democratic appeal—they could be made by anyone; they could be seen by all. Both medium and message spoke of democracy, which made posters ideal for expressing American war aims: why we fight, what we fight for.
Benjamin Spock was an American pediatrician best known for his book Baby and Child Care. He was also active in the anti-Vietnam War movements during the 1960's and early 1970's.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Spock War Posters Collection consists of approximately 220 posters relating to World War I, World War II, and the Vietnam War. Dr. Spock is specifically mentioned in several of the Vietnam-era posters. Common themes of the posters include morale-boosting, fund-raising, recruiting and civil defense. Organizations represented include the Red Cross; U.S. Army, Navy, Air Force and Marine Corps; various relief committees; and other groups involved directly or indirectly in the war effort. The vast majority of the items are American but there are also a few from France, Canada, Italy and England.
Arrangement of the Collection
Posters are subdivided by the war to which they relate. Within that, items have been assigned identification numbers and are arranged in order by number.
Related Material
See also the
War Posters Collection
(World War I and World War II).
Subject and Genre Headings
Military history; Avedon, Richard.; Grossman, Robert, 1940-; Haeberle, Ron, 1941-; Hofmann, William.; Israel, Marvin.; Lennon, John, 1940-1980.; Negrin, Su.; Spock, Benjamin, 1903-1998.; American Red Cross -- Posters.; United States. -- Army. -- Posters.; United States. -- Army. -- Air Service -- Posters.; United States. -- Navy -- Posters.; United States. -- Marine Corps -- Posters.; Liberty bonds -- Posters.; Recruiting and enlistment -- Posters.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States -- Posters.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- United States -- Posters.; War posters, American.; War posters, Canadian.; War posters, French.; War posters, Italian.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Posters.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Posters.; Calendars (documents); Posters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Benjamin Spock.
Inventory
- World War I
  - Join the Air Service & Serve In France, 1917; SPOCK-WWI-1; 96cm / 64cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Air Service
    Description: Soldiers & a military plane
    Printer: Ketterling, Philadelphia
  - 10,000,000 Members by Christmas, SPOCK-WWI-2; 28cm / 53cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: American Red Cross
    Description: Candle in a window
  - Ten Million New Members By Christmas, SPOCK-WWI-3; 76cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
  - [no caption], SPOCK-WWI-4; 77cm / 52cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: American Red Cross worker reaching out her hand
  - [no caption], SPOCK-WWI-5; 72cm / 101cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Red Cross medical van
  - GUILD OF PLAY St. Nicholas Home for Raid-Shock Children, 1917; SPOCK-WWI-6; 77cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: Foster families
    Description: St. Nicholas surrounded by dancing girls
    Printer: Sanders, Phillips & Co. Ltd., The Baynard Press, London
  - On Les aura! 2E Emprunt de La Defense Nationale – Souscruez, 1916; SPOCK-WWI-7; 114cm / 80cm black, white and brown (Map-case 55)
    Type: French
    Description: Soldier running
    Printer: Devambez Imp., Paris
  - Sous le Patronage de (Secretariant Francais des Villages Liberes) Theatre des Arts, SPOCK-WWI-8; 115cm / 80cm multi (Map-case 56)
    Description: Woman & child
    Printer: Imp. H. Chachoin, Paris
  - Emprunt De La Liberation – On les a souscriver a la London Country & Westminster Bank Paris, SPOCK-WWI-9; 120cm / 80cm multi (Map-case 56)
    Description: Various soldiers at war
    Printer: Imprimerie de Vaugirard, Paris
  - Journee Nationale Des Tuberculeaux, SPOCK-WWI-10; 80cm / 114cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldier standing by blooming tree & pasture
    Printer: Devambez, Imp. Paris
  - Lend Your Money To Your Government//Buy A U.S. Government Bond, 2nd Liberty Loan of 1917/, SPOCK-WWI-11; 92cm / 122cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: Government Bonds
    Description: Capital building
    Printer: American Lithographic Co., NY
  - Ring It Again – Buy US Government Bonds – 3d Liberty Loan, SPOCK-WWI-12; 2 copies 77cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Colonial scene
    Printer: Sackett & Wilhelms Corp., NY
  - "Shall we be more tender with our dollars than with the Lives of our sons?", 1917; SPOCK-WWI-13; 76cm / 50cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Uncle Sam reaching out & pointing at a marching army
    Printer: Illinois Litho. Co. Chicago
  - Ring It Again – Buy A U.S. Government Bond of the 2nd Liberty Loan of 1917, SPOCK-WWI-14; 77cm / 51cm red, white, blue and brown (Map-case 55)
    Description: Liberty bell
    Printer: Ketterlinus, Philada.
  - Before Sunset Buy A US Government Bond of the 2nd Liberty Loan of 1917, SPOCK-WWI-15; 2 copies 77cm / 51cm red, white and blue (Map-case 55)
    Description: Statue of Liberty at sunset
    Printer: Sackett & Wilhelms Corporation, New York
  - "Shall We Be More Tender With Our Dollars That With The Lives of Our Sons?" 2nd Liberty Loan of 1917, SPOCK-WWI-16; 2 copies 77cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldier & sailor with an American Flag
    Printer: Edwards & Deutsch Litho. Co. Chicago
  - Our Daddy Is Fighting at the Front for YOU – Back Him Up 2nd LIBERTY LOAN of 1917, SPOCK-WWI-17; 2 copies 77cm / 51cm red, white and blue (Map-case 55)
    Description: 2 small children, boy holding an American Flag
    Printer: T.F. Moore Co. New York
  - Are You 100% American? Prove It! Buy US Government Bonds – 3d Liberty Loan/, SPOCK-WWI-18; 77cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Eagle & American Flags
  - Help our Town win the right to fly this Flag... 3d Liberty Loan Honor Roll..., SPOCK-WWI-19; 64cm / 97cm red, white, and blue (Map-case 55)
    Description: Flag flying
    Printer: Capital Pub. Inc., Washington, D.C.
  - Over The Top For You – Buy US Government Bonds – 3d Liberty Loan, SPOCK-WWI-20; 76cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldier running with an American Flag
    Printer: Kitterlinus, Phila.
  - "Good Bye, Dad, I'm Off To Fight For Old Glory, You Buy US GOV'T BONDS", SPOCK-WWI-21; 77cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Son shaking father's hand
  - Prestito Nazionale Rendita Consolidata 5% netto... Della Banca D'Italia, SPOCK-WWI-22; 34cm / 24cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: Italian
    Description: Soldier climbing a damaged tree
    Printer: Officine Dell ' l stituto Italtiano D'Arti Grafiche - Bergamo
  - Fate tutti il vostro dovere! Le Sottoscrizionial Prestito Siricevono Presso Il Credito Italiano, SPOCK-WWI-23; 101cm / 70cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldier holding a gun in the battlefield
    Printer: G. Modiano & Co. – Milano
  - Make Your Dollars End The War, Your Liberty Your Forefathers Died For Is At Stake If You Can't Fight Your Money Can – Buy A Liberty Bond & Uncle Sam Will Do The Rest, 1917; SPOCK-WWI-24; 96cm / 61cm red, white and blue (Map-case 55)
    Type: Liberty Bonds
    Printer: Washington: GPO
  - Hun – His Mark – Blot it out with Liberty Bonds, SPOCK-WWI-25; 77cm / 51cm red, white and black (Map-case 55)
    Description: Bloodied handprint
    Printer: Manz Engraving Co., Chi.
  - Hun or Home? Buy More Liberty Bonds, SPOCK-WWI-26; 77cm / 51cm black, cream and red (Map-case 55)
    Description: Mother holding a baby, Hun approaching
  - Buy Liberty Bonds "That Government of the People, Buy the People, For the People shall Not Perish From the Earth" A. Lincoln, SPOCK-WWI-27; 77cm / 51cm Brown, green and orange (Map-case 55)
    Description: Profile of Lincoln
  - Come On! Buy More Liberty Bonds, 1918; SPOCK-WWI-28; 74cm / 50cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldier on the battlefield
    Printer: Strobridge Litho. Co.
  - To-day buy that liberty bond, SPOCK-WWI-29; 72cm / 56cm red, white, and blue (Map-case 55)
    Description: Sun peaking over a hill (the logo for liberty bonds)
  - That Liberty Shall Not Perish From the Earth – Buy Liberty Bonds – Fourth Liberty Loan, SPOCK-WWI-30; 104cm / 71cm Orange and browns (Map-case 55)
    Description: New York & the Statue of Liberty burning & destroyed
    Printer: Haywood Strasser & Voight Litho. Co., N.Y. Imp.
  - Beat Back the Hun with Liberty Bonds, SPOCK-WWI-31; 77cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Hun with bloodied hands & bayonet
  - Must Children Die & Mothers Plead In Vain? Buy More Liberty Bonds, SPOCK-WWI-32; 102cm / 76cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Mother holding children & reaching out her hand for help
    Printer: Sackett & Wilhelms Corporation, N.Y.
  - Enlist! On Which Side of the Window Are You?, 1917; SPOCK-WWI-33; 99cm / 66cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: Recruitment Poster
    Description: Man looking out a window at passing soldiers
    Printer: National Printing & Eng. Co. Chicago, USA, Geo. F/ Griffin, Chicago, Ill.
  - Going, Going, Gone!... Aviation Section, Signal Corps, SPOCK-WWI-34; 107cm / 78cm black, orange and cream (Map-case 55)
    Type: Signal Corps
    Description: Black & white photos of SPOCK-WWI-planes & an orange arrow
  - US ARMY – Develops all a man has of courage, it makes a strong body, & trains the mind to disciplined decision – ENLIST!, 24 Apr 1916; SPOCK-WWI-35; 107cm / 73cm blue and white (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Army
  - U.S. Marines – Be A Sea Soldier, SPOCK-WWI-36; 103cm / 76cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Marine Corps
    Description: Marine sitting with his gun
  - Father Of Our Country Appealed For Soldiers As Follows... Do As Our Forefathers Did in 1776 – ENLIST – Army Recruiting Office, SPOCK-WWI-37; 108cm / 71cm blue and white (Map-case 55)
    Printer: Ryan & Hart Co., Printers, Chicago
  - U.S. Army Medical Department Wanted For The Hospital Corps., SPOCK-WWI-38; 72cm / 45cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Boy with a bugle announcing the details of the offer
    Printer: Eckert Lithographing Co. Washington, D.C.
  - I Want YOU For The US Army – Nearest Recruiting Station, 1917; SPOCK-WWI-39; 102cm / 76cm red, white, and blue (Map-case 55)
    Description: Uncle Sam Poster
    Printer: Leslie-Judge Co., N.Y.
  - Blood or Bread? Others are giving their blood You will shorten the war – save life if you eat only what you need, & waste nothing, SPOCK-WWI-40; 74cm / 54cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Food Administration
    Description: Soldiers carrying wounded soldier
    Printer: Forbes, Boston
  - Uncle Sam Needs That Extra Shovelful... U.S. Fuel Administration, SPOCK-WWI-41; 71cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Fuel Administration
    Description: Uncle Sam standing with a man shoveling coal into a fire
    Printer: Latham Litho. & Ptg. Co. Brooklyn, NY
  - First to Fight "Democracy's Vanguard" US Marine Corps... Real Fighting with Real Fighters, 1917; SPOCK-WWI-42; 102cm / 76cm white, black, and blue (Map-case 55)
    Description: Marines running onto the beach
  - Spirit of 1917 – Join the U.S. Marines & be the First Line of Defense on Land or Sea, SPOCK-WWI-43; 102cm / 76cm green and white / multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Marines marching & carrying flags
  - US Marines "Soldiers of the Sea", SPOCK-WWI-44; 102cm / 76cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Marines
    Description: Soldiers running through a field, battleships in the background
  - US Marines – First To Fight In France for Freedom – Enlist with the "Soldiers of the Sea", SPOCK-WWI-45; 102cm / 76cm green, white, and multi colored (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldiers at war
  - Follow the Boys in Blue for Home & Country – Enlist in the Navy, SPOCK-WWI-46; 53cm / 74cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Navy
    Description: Sailors/Men boarding a battleship
    Printer: Color plates by Gill Engraving Co. NY
  - He is Getting Our Country's Signal ARE YOU? JOIN THE NAVY..., SPOCK-WWI-47; 2 copies 77cm / 50cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Sailor holding a flag
  - Will You Supply Eyes for the Navy?... Will You Help Us "Stand Watch" on a Destroyer, SPOCK-WWI-48; 26cm / 17cm teal and white (Map-case 55)
    Description: Blindfolded captain on a destroyer
  - Only The Navy Can Stop This, SPOCK-WWI-49; 2 copies 65cm / 50cm black, white, and red (Map-case 55)
    Description: Enemy soldier with bloodied sword, killing women & children
    Printer: US Navy Publicity Bureau, New York
  - Will You Supply Eyes for the Navy?... Will You Help Us "Stand Watch" on a Destroyer?, SPOCK-WWI-50; 73cm / 52cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Captain blindfolded on a ship
  - Your Country Needs You! Join the Navy Now!... Apply Recruiting Station or Navy League, SPOCK-WWI-51; 63cm / 48cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Sailor playing a bugle
  - A Wonderful Opportunity for YOU, Ashore, On Leave – U.S. Navy, SPOCK-WWI-52; 71cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Sailor going ashore with bags
  - "We Have Met The Enemy & They Are Ours" - The Navy's First U-Boat Capture Lad! If You Want Action, Get In The Game & Enlist In The Navy Recruiting Stations Everywhere, SPOCK-WWI-53; 36cm / 43cm black, white, and red (Map-case 55)
    Description: Black & white photo of sailors on a U-Boat
    Printer: Press of the U.S. Navy Recruiting Bureau, New York
  - NAVY! Uncle Sam is calling you! ENLIST in the Navy! DO IT NOW!, 1917; SPOCK-WWI-54; 36cm / 27cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Uncle Sam
    Printer: Leslie-Judge Co., NY
  - What the Navy is doing... The Road to France – The Navy keeps it open... Enlist in the Navy, SPOCK-WWI-55; 36cm / 43cm black, white and red (Map-case 55)
    Description: Black & white photos of various Navy occurences
    Printer: US Navy Recruiting Bureau, New York
  - Join the Navy the Service for Fighting Men Naval Reserve Wants Unlimited Number of Men Right Away Apply at any Naval Recruiting Office, SPOCK-WWI-56; 107cm / 72cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Sailor riding a missile through the water
  - Your Country Needs You – Join The Navy!... America's First Line of Action Be One of the Leaders in Your Community by Enlisting TODAY! "First, Last, & Always – USA", 1916; SPOCK-WWI-57; 49cm / 37cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Sailor saluting
    Printer: Corp. Knapp Co., Inc., NY
  - Your Country Calls – Join the Navy – For Information Apply Recruiting Station or Navy League, SPOCK-WWI-58; 19cm / 30cm red, white, and blue (Map-case 55)
    Description: ---
  - [no caption], 1918; SPOCK-WWI-59; 76cm / 50cm black and white (Map-case 55)
    Description: Battleship & a shipyard
    Printer: Heywood Strasser & Voight Litho. Co., NY, Imp.
  - What The Navy Is Doing – Convoying In Winter.. .", SPOCK-WWI-60; 36cm / 43cm black, white, and red (Map-case 55)
    Description: Black & white photos of Navy men in the winter
    Printer: Press of the Navy Recruiting Bureau, NY
  - On The Job For Victory – U.S. Shipping Board, Emergency Fleet Corporation, SPOCK-WWI-61; 76cm / 102cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Shipping Board
    Description: Shipyard
    Printer: W.F. Powers Co. Litho., N.Y. Issued by Publication Section, Emergency Fleet Corporation, Philadelphia, PA
  - Treat 'Em Rough! Join the Tanks, U.S. Tank Corps. Open To All Fighting Men - All Classes - 18 to 45, SPOCK-WWI-62; 56cm / 35 cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: U.S. Tank Corps
    Description: "Black Tom", mascot of the US Tank Corps
  - United We Serve – YMCA, YWCA. National Catholic Was Council – K. of C., Jewish Welfare Board, SPOCK-WWI-63; 2 copies 77cm / 50cm Brown, red, white, and blue (Map-case 55)
    Type: United War Work Campaign
  - Civilians – When We Go Through This We Need All The Help & Comfort You Can Give The Jewish Welfare Board, 1918; SPOCK-WWI-64; 2 copies 84cm / 56cm blue and browns (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldier with raised arms
    Printer: Alco-Gravure, Inc., NY
  - YMCA... "I wish unreservedly to commend its work for the Army". Pershing United War Work Campaign, November 11-18, 1918, March,1918; SPOCK-WWI-65; 84cm / 56 cm Cream, brown and red (Map-case 55)
    Description: Portrait of Pershing
    Printer: Alco-Gravure, Inc. NY
  - "Hey Fellows!" Your Money Brings the Book We Need When We Want It American Library Association United Work Campaign – Week of November 11, 1918, SPOCK-WWI-66; 2 copies 76cm / 51cm white, browns, and orange (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldiers with books – one soldier calling to others
    Printer: Committee on Public Information, Division of Pictorial Publicity
  - This Church is Behind the United War Work Campaign, SPOCK-WWI-67; 64cm / 47cm grey and blue (Map-case 55)
  - For Your Boy – United War Work Campaign – November 11-18, 1918, SPOCK-WWI-68; 2 copies 77cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldier receiving coffee from a YMCA man
    Printer: Ketterlinus, Phila.
  - For Home & Country – Victory Liberty Loan, 1918; SPOCK-WWI-69; 2 copies 102cm / 76cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: Victory Liberty Loan
    Description: Soldier holding his son, hugging his wife
    Printer: American Lithographic Co., N.Y.
  - They Keep the Sea-Lanes Open – Invest in the Victory Liberty Loan, SPOCK-WWI-70; 2 copies 75cm / 100cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Sailors on submarines & battleships at war
    Printer: W.F. Powers Co. Litho., N.Y.
  - And They Thought We Couldn't Fight – Victory Liberty Loan, SPOCK-WWI-71; 3 copies 105cm / 78cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Soldier triumphant on the battlefield
  - Americans All!... Victory Liberty Loan, 1919; SPOCK-WWI-72; 2 copies 102cm / 68cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Figure of Liberty with an American Flag
  - Americans All!... Victory Liberty Loan, 1919; SPOCK-WWI-73; 102cm / 68cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Figure of Liberty with American Flag
  - Sure! We'll Finish the Job – Victory Liberty Loan, 1918; SPOCK-WWI-74; 2 copies 96cm / 66cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Man in overhauls reaching into his pocket
    Printer: Edwards & Deutsch Litho. Co., Chicago
  - Our £100,000 Submarine – You Can Help Buy War Bonds – Business Men's Week, SPOCK-WWI-75; 51cm / 37cm black, white, blue, and yellow (Map-case 55)
    Type: War Bonds
    Printer: Johnson, Riddle & Co., Ltd., London SE
  - Clear The Way!! Buy Bonds Fourth Liberty Union, SPOCK-WWI-76; 76cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Description: Figure of Liberty with an American flag, watching over sailors at a gun
  - We can't all go... but we can all help! Put at least 10% of your pay in War Bonds..., 1941; SPOCK-WWI-77; 56cm / 43cm red, white and black (Map-case 55)
    Description: Black & white photo of a soldier holding a crying child
  - Remember Belgium – Buy Bonds Fourth Liberty Loan, SPOCK-WWI-78; 77cm / 51cm green, yellow, orange, and black (Map-case 55)
    Description: Girl being led away by an enemy soldier
    Printer: U.S. Prtg. & Litho. Co., NY
  - Canada's Weak Spot... Are You Satisfied, SPOCK-WWI-79; 89cm / 61cm multi (Map-case 55)
    Type: War Bonds – Canada
    Description: Canadians buying bonds in comparison to Great Britain & the USA
  - Save Your Child From Autocracy & Poverty Buy War Saving Stamps (U.S. Treasury) War Saving Stamps Issued by the U.S. Government, SPOCK-WWI-80; 102cm / 76cm white, brown, yellow, blue, and green (Map-case 55)
    Type: War Saving Stamps
    Description: Child standing with the hand from the Statue of Liberty
  - Dedicated to the Boy Scouts of America "We'll Help You to Win the War, Dad", with War Saving Stamps, SPOCK-WWI-81; 71cm / 46cm Brown, gray, white, and black (Map-case 56)
    Description: Boy Scout & Father in soldier's uniform
    Printer: William J. Tully
  - Save & Invest in the Safest, Simplest Security buy W.S.S...., SPOCK-WWI-82; 62cm / 44cm black, blue, and white (Map-case 56)
    Printer: Government Printing Office
  - YMCA His Home Over There – More Than 2000 Such Homes for Our Boys United War Work Campaign, November 11th – 18th, SPOCK-WWI-83; 2 copies 105cm / 71cm multi (Map-case 56)
    Type: YMCA
    Description: Soldier walking towards inviting YMCA building
- World War I, U.S. Army recruitment posters
  - Men Wanted For the Army, 1909; 106cm / 76cm multicolor (Map-case 56)
    Description: Soldier on horseback with bugle, soldier with bugle standing beside the horse
    Artist: Michael P. Whelam
    Printer: n/a
    Condition: VERY damaged, large sections missing; enclosed in plastic, not numbered
  - Men Wanted For the Army, 1909; 106cm / 76cm multicolor (Map-case 56)
    Description: Soldiers in dress uniforms in a tropical setting
    Condition: Some edges missing; enclosed in plastic, not numbered
  - Men Wanted For the Army, 1909; 106cm / 76cm multicolor (Map-case 56)
    Description: Soldiers fixing plane, young soldier speaking to older soldier in foreground
    Condition: Very damaged
- World War II
  - Our Women Are Doing Their Bit, SPOCK-WWII-1; 67cm / 48cm red, white and black (Map-case 57)
    Description: Red Cross
  - Make Good The Promise. 2nd War Fund, SPOCK-WWII-2; 31cm / 43cm multi (Map-case 57)
    Description: Pot of gold
  - New Haven Red Cross Must Raise $200,000, SPOCK-WWII-3; 57cm / 36cm red, white, and blue (Map-case 57)
    Printer: Wilson H. Lee Company, New Haven
  - This Device on Hat or Helmet Means US Marines, SPOCK-WWII-4; 107cm / 72cm white, green and yellow (Map-case 57)
    Description: Marine emblem
  - ENEMY is listening – He wants to know what you know –, SPOCK-WWII-5; 71cm / 51cm red, white, and black (Map-case 57)
    Type: Enemy spies
    Printer: GPO
  - Bits Of Careless Talk Are Pieced Together By The Enemy, SPOCK-WWII-6; 71cm / 51cm multi (Map-case 57)
    Type: Enemy Spies
    Description: Hand w/ Nazi ring putting together puzzle
    Printer: US Government Printing Press
  - "Come on in. I'll treat you right.", 1937; 1969; SPOCK-WWII-7; 75cm / 56cm multi (Map-case 57)
    Type: Foreign Seduction
    Description: "Any Youth" being seduced by "War"
    Printer: MacFadden Publications, Inc. – Renewed by Liberty Library Corp.